export const quizData = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is the basic unit of heredity?",
    options: ["Gene", "Chromosome", "Protein", "Cell"],
    answer: "Gene",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Which scientist is known as the father of genetics?",
    options: [
      "Charles Darwin",
      "Gregor Mendel",
      "James Watson",
      "Rosalind Franklin",
    ],
    answer: "Gregor Mendel",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "What is the process by which species change over time?",
    options: ["Mutation", "Evolution", "Natural Selection", "Adaptation"],
    answer: "Evolution",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "What is the term for the physical characteristics of an organism?",
    options: ["Phenotype", "Genotype", "Allele", "Homozygous"],
    answer: "Phenotype",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "Which of the following is an example of a recessive trait?",
    options: ["Brown eyes", "Attached earlobes", "Curly hair", "Tall height"],
    answer: "Attached earlobes",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "What is the term for an organism with two different alleles for a trait?",
    options: ["Homozygous", "Heterozygous", "Dominant", "Recessive"],
    answer: "Heterozygous",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "What is the term for the genetic makeup of an organism?",
    options: ["Phenotype", "Genotype", "Allele", "Homozygous"],
    answer: "Genotype",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "Which scientist is credited with the discovery of the structure of DNA?",
    options: [
      "Charles Darwin",
      "Gregor Mendel",
      "James Watson",
      "Rosalind Franklin",
    ],
    answer: "James Watson",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "What is the term for a change in an organism's DNA?",
    options: ["Mutation", "Evolution", "Natural Selection", "Adaptation"],
    answer: "Mutation",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "Which of the following is an example of an acquired trait?",
    options: ["Eye color", "Height", "Musical talent", "Blood type"],
    answer: "Musical talent",
  },
];
